Nathan Lilienthal

nathan@nixpulvis.com o https://nixpulvis.com o +1-202-701-4368

Summary: I'm a flexible programmer with a focus on efficiency, user experience, and writing solid, maintainable code. I have 6+ years of experience working in a variety of environments, from small scale companies, to fortune 500 companies. I'm happy to work either in an office, remote, or a hybrid schedule.

Languages: Rust, Java, Ruby, C/C++, LUA, Racket, Shell. Java/Typescript, Python, and more...

Systems: UNIX, Linux, Git + Hub/Lab, Rails, Heroku, Postgres (PostGIS), SQLite, AVR/ARM, WoW (ask me about it).

Professional Experience

• Software Engineer

2021 - 2022

Aetion Inc.

Remote / Boston, MA

- Profiled and optimized core platform routines, as well as contributed to broader efforts to design new architecture for efficiently running our large analytic jobs
- Developed a standalone Java tool to assist with templated spreadsheet population for science team deliverables
- Worked on-call for production issues ranging from identifying user-error, workarounds, and long term solutions.

• Research Programmer

2019 - 2021

Northeastern University, Intelligence Advanced Research Projects Activity (IARPA)

Boston, MA

- Collaboratively developed a hybrid-mode secure programming language design for multi-party computation (MPC)
- Represented my team at both remote and in-person technical exchange meetings with other researchers
- Built a prototype implementation of our language, which is forked from the Rust programming language

• Sr. Software Engineer

2018 - 2019

Forward Financing Inc.

Boston, MA

- Developed a client wrapper library for an Algolia search implementation
- Quickly performed various application performance improvements, making use of Scout APM and other tools
- Planned architecture refactoring, including object model improvements and a new data permissions system
- Led efforts to create an orchestration CLI for managing a complex Heroku + Salesforce microservice system

• Software Engineer

2016 - 2017

Apple Inc.

Cupertino, CA

- Built a Ruby library (radic) and CLI (radish) for interacting with Apple's bug management system (aka Radar)
- Participated in a cross-functional web design work group to help create common components for the hardware teams
- Contributed to an internal tool for managing hardware validation, inspired in part by Travis CI
- Contributed to an internal tool for analysing large amounts of pre-production device test data

Notable Projects

- alacritty, a cross-platform, GPU-accelerated terminal emulator (contributor)
- galos, an Elite: Dangerous ZMQ subscriber, database, and starmap
- oursh, a multi-language shell which aims to be POSIX compatible, written in Rust
- lalrpop-lambda, parser and reductions for the lambda calculus with a minimal webapp
- nrf24101, basic working AVR firmware for the Nordic Semiconductor's nRF24L01+ radio transceiver

Education & Coops/Internships

• Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

 ${\bf 2011-2016}$

Northeastern University

Boston, MA

- Teaching Assistant, Fundamentals of Computer Science 1

Fall of 2012, 2013, 2014, and 2015

- Independent Study, Multi2Sim - A Heterogeneous System Simulator

Fall 2014

Summer 2012

• Software Developer – Intern

HOMER Energy

Boulder, CO

Software Developer – Full-time Coop

Jan. 2013 – June 2013

Bluesocket - Adtran

Burlington, MA

• Web Developer – Full-time Coop Americas Test Kitchen Jan. 2014 – June 2014

Americas Test Kuchen

Boston, MA

Jan. 2015 - Aug. 2015

• Software Engineer – Full-time Coop *Apple Inc.*

Cupertino, CA